<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brenden Sosnader</title>
    <description>Hi, I&#39;m Brenden Sosnader. I study computer science at Penn State University and I like to make things. This is where I show them off.
</description>
    <link>http://sosnader.tk/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sosnader.tk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 18:28:56 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 18:28:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Shall Know Our Velocity!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/velocity.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;velocity cover&quot; /&gt;
Before we continue, I need to warn you–this is a Dave Eggers book. If you’re not a fan of Dave Eggers, don’t even bother considering reading this book. You probably won’t like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t really know what it is that I like so much about Eggers’ writing (other than &lt;em&gt;The Circle&lt;/em&gt;, which I &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; like), but, much like &lt;em&gt;A Heartbreaking Work of Staggering Genius,&lt;/em&gt;  this book also taps into something deeply emotional inside me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book follows the path of two friends who have decided to travel the world in one week. One of them has apparently came into a large sum of money, and wants to get rid of it as quickly as possible. Their plan is to hand out random wads of cash to people they think deserve it in every location they’re in. It actually raises a lot of questions about charity in general. Is it right to give away money only to those you feel &lt;em&gt;deserve&lt;/em&gt; it? To expect people to behave a certain way just in the hopes that you’ll deem them worthy of your money? On the surface, it seems obvious that they’re doing a good thing for people. But the way some of the recipients react to the money makes you question it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also an interesting plot device that makes its way halfway into the book. Eggers actually revised the book, adding 49 extra pages that actually pretty heavily influence what’s going on. It’s really unique, and another part of the reason why I like Eggers so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the book is about traveling, I recommend reading it (if you ever bother) during some sort of travel. It really enhances the feelings and emotions you get while reading it. Anyway, from now on I’ll try to avoid any more Dave Eggers and stick to books that people might actually enjoy reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/01/25/you-shall-know-our-velocity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/01/25/you-shall-know-our-velocity.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gerrymandering</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Gerrymandering. It’s a political term heard in the media often, flung at both Democrats and Republicans alike. Typically connotated as negative, it’s been picking up steam as the rhetoric against “corrupt politicians” has become increasingly more popular. However, before immediately deciding on its efficacy one way or another, it’s important to understand what it is, and where it came from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The definition of gerrymandering is “to manipulate the boundaries of (an electoral constituency) so as to favor one party or class.” Voting districts for state or federal congressional districts can be shaped in ways to include or exclude certain areas of the population. For instance, if a politician knows that one area of town supports him, but another does not, he would prefer it if his district only included the people who do support him, to better his chances of winning. This type of shaping can silence the voices of people who would vote against the party in charge of the districting by splitting them up and diluting their voting power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/gerrymander.png&quot; alt=&quot;gerrymandering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The origin of the funny little word itself is a portmanteau of “salamander” and “Gerry.” The Gerry comes from the last name of a certain Elbridge Gerry, who, in 1812, did just what the definition says–reshaped his district to favor his party. The shape was said to look somewhat like a salamander, and the name stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what has the history of gerrymandering looked like, and how does it affect the political parties of today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 19th and early 20th century, the majority of gerrymandered districts were due to racism. The aim of many district-drawers in deep southern states was to weaken the voting powers of African Americans as much as possible. Because African Americans typically tended to vote Democrat, not Republican, the districts in these mostly Republican states were drawn to prevent the minorities from having a say in their governance. That’s not to say Democrats didn’t do it as well. Gerrymandering has a long history with both political parties spanning back many decades. It’s a tool that’s been used by corrupt politicans on both sides of the aisle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/gerry2.png&quot; alt=&quot;gerrymandering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after the Voting Rights Act of 1965, things started to change. Laws were drawn preventing disctrics from being drawn in a way to disenfranchise minority voters, and a few of the worst offending states were required to submit any new districts to the Department of Justice for review. Furthermore, some new districts were actually purposefully gerrymandered to create so-called “majority-minority” districts, where a district was drawn specifically to give a voice to a minority community in an area. This demonstrates how gerrymandering is not always for a nefarious purpose. If there is a town that has 70% of one community and 30% of another, and you have to split it into two districts, there are a few options you have. You could split it right down the middle, giving each district 35% of the majority and 15% of the minority. However, now the majority will have the loudest voice in both districts, completely shutting off the minority. If you instead draw a larger district encompassing just the 70%, and a smaller one just encompassing the 30%, you get one district which represents the majority, and one which represents the minority. It’s still technically “unfair,” but it allows minorities to not get shut out of representation–especially in the light of the decades of racism and discrimination preceding (and following) the Voting Rights Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, even these sorts of districts can cause problems. In recent years, many “safe” red states have gained increasing amounts of minority populations. When populations increase, districts must be redrawn to accomodate them. One might assume that the best way to do it fairly would be using the “majority-minority” districting from above. However, that can be disenfranchising as well. If you have three typically red districts, each which have gained a large amount of a minority, you might be at risk of losing all of them, if enough minorty support swings them. If you instead funnel all those minorities into one &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; district, you can give them one district, but keep your original three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/gerry5.png&quot; alt=&quot;gerry 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what’s gerrymandering like today? In 2010, a wave of hardcore Republican “Tea Party” politicians were voted into office. The timing, along with the 2010 census, meant these people were in charge of drawing new districts. Unsurprisingly, they gerrymandered the hell out of them. For the past 7 years now, Republicans in the House of Representatives have enjoyed a majority in part due to their control of state legislature and governances which lead to favorable districts for the House. The Republican party, in the past several years, has been more effective at gaining support in state and local politics, which allows them to have the groudwork to get more Congressmen elected, using, among other things, gerrymandering. Is it unfair? Yes. Is it legal? Also yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current, one-sided use of gerrymandering by the Republican party is indicative of the growing divide between the two parties in Congress. It’s also indicative of the Democrats failure to mobilize grassroots as effectively as the Republicans. The Democrats must change their tactics if they want to overcome the effect decimination of their support that the Republicans have set in motion. It’s actually quite shocking to realize that even with the massive shifts in demographics that have occured in the past decades, mostly in favor of groups that vote Democrat, the majority of states are Republican-controlled, Republicans have a majority in the Senate and the House, and a Republican is in the Oval Office. It’s a combination of Republican voter-supression tactics, gerrymandering, but also a Democratic failure to capitalize on the shifting political landscape. One thing is certain, however–gerrymandering breaks the democratic process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there solutions? Once again, yes, but it will take a long time before we see change. Gerrymandering is used by both parties go keep their power, and those who got elected due to gerrymandering are hardly going to turn around and destroy the very thing that gave them their power. But what can be done? Some states use nonpartisan committees to draw boundaries instead of the politicans, but even these committees can be infiltrated with partisanship. There are also computer algorithms which can draw perfectly “fair” districts, which seem quite promising, when looking at the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/gerry3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;gerrymandering 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results are quite different than the original, snaking, convoluted districts. Problem solved, right? Not exactly. These kinds of districts forego some of the positive possibilities of gerrymandering–allowing minorities to get representation where they otherwise would not. It’s likely that the best solution will involve a combination of computer algorithms and committees. For now, we’ll just have to deal with this being considered “fair representation:”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/gerry4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;gerrymandering 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources:
http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2012/09/the-twisted-history-of-gerrymandering-in-american-politics/262369/#slide7
https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/the-power-that-gerrymandering-has-brought-to-republicans/2016/06/17/045264ae-2903-11e6-ae4a-3cdd5fe74204_story.html
http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/10/the-league-of/309084/
https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2014/06/03/this-computer-programmer-solved-gerrymandering-in-his-spare-time/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/civic-issues/2017/01/25/gerrymandering.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/civic-issues/2017/01/25/gerrymandering.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>civic-issues</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Topics for Civic Issues and Passion Blogs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My passion blog will be the same: books! There’s so many more books (obviously). I may also do some negative reviews. For the Civic Issues blog, I’ve decided I want to talk about party politics and some things that have changed and occurred to affect that over the years. It should be interesting, and I have a lot I could talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2017/01/18/topics-for-blogs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2017/01/18/topics-for-blogs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rcl</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This I Believe First Draft</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, I liked to argue. A LOT. I debated endlessly with my parents, fiercely combating against what I saw to be completely arbitrary rules, regulations, and restrictions. I remember one time, when I wanted to stay up late on a school night. My dad countered my request, saying, “But you’ll be exhausted tomorrow morning!” I shook my head, and he acquiesced. I was triumphant! Yet, just as he had said, the next morning was hell. When gently asked if I was tired, I stoically refused to admit it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew up, my stubbornness softened. I still kept my love of debate, but I no longer stuck to my guns as firmly as I had as a child. The turning point came one day, in high school English class, when I was arguing with my friend about some topic we had learned in class. He made a particularly good point, and I suddenly realized he was right. I agreed with him. I knew I had lost, yet, it was freeing to be able to change my mind, accept a new answer, and move on. I believe in this sort of discourse. Often, people simply repeat their own rhetoric, never actually looking at the facts or making an informed decision. This attitude emphasizes a “right versus wrong” mentality, instead of one of collaboration and learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in being able to accept a new viewpoint, because without that skill, I would never have been able to learn as much as I have, both inside and outside of a classroom. Being able to rationally and coherently debate differing views, and being willing to accept when one is wrong, is essential for progress. Too often people are caught up in how they feel and what they believe, instead of listening to the facts in front of them. I believe it is necessary to be able to step back, look at the big picture, and reforge one’s ideas and beliefs in the face of new information. Without that ability, we will be lost to increasing divisions and disagreements. Let’s not agree to disagree, let’s agree to debate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2017/01/18/this-i-believe-first-draft.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2017/01/18/this-i-believe-first-draft.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rcl</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Test Post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing, testing…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/civic-issues/2017/01/12/test-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/civic-issues/2017/01/12/test-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>civic-issues</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ideas for Passion Blog and Civic Issues Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For my passion blog, I’m planning on doing the same topic as before–books! I’ve still got a lot to share. For my civic issues blog, I’m thinking a good topic might be looking at new legislation that is proposed/passed under the new presidency, and what kind of impacts and effects it may have, and how it differs from previous legislation. Another topic could be about party politics and how it has changed over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the “This I Believe” project, I have two ideas. The first is bascially, “I believe in doing things I enjoy.” Often we are pushed to do things because they will help us get a job, or look good on a resume, and so on. Yet, for me, that’s not worth it. I do things because of what they mean to me. Another one would basically be “I believe in discourse.” I firmly and strongy believe that everyone should be open to discussion and argument and be able to accept when they are wrong and accept new viewpoints. Being able to calmly discuss issues and bring up factual, well reasoned arguments are extremely important to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2017/01/11/ideas-for-blogs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2017/01/11/ideas-for-blogs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rcl</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making a Webapp with AngularJS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It hadn’t yet been a day since I’d been home for winter break, and I already had grown bored of just sitting around. Sure, we all dream of the promised land after the semester is over, where there are no responsibilities and no homework, and where finals are nothing but a faint memory in our heads, but in reality, it gets old, fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of finals, though, there’s a peculiar phenonenom the seems to occur during the last week or so of the semester—college students, instead of studying, will inevitably spend all of their free time calculating the lowest possible grade they can get on their finals to still get the grade they want in their classes. I’m not immune to it myself—it’s fun, and quite frankly relieving, to discover you only need a 65% on your CS final to get an A in the course. And if you look online, you’ll find there’s plenty of websites that do the calculations for you. I decided to make one too.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to cure my boredom and learn at the same time, so I decided to make it using something I haven’t really had experience with before: &lt;a href=&quot;https://angular.io&quot;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt;. Although this idea has been done plenty of times before, I thought it would be a nice way to experiment with AngularJS. You can find the finished project &lt;a href=&quot;http://sosnader.tk/grade-calc&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I faced a few challenges in getting this project up and running, but all in all it only took me the better part of a Sunday afternoon. The biggest challenge that I had to overcome was to actually figure out how AngularJS worked. I had really never touched any sort of Javascript framework before this point and I didn’t really understand the concept. After going through some tutorials and example code on the AngularJS website, I felt ready enough to tackle the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Angular team makes it really easy to get a project up and running with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cli.angular.io/&quot;&gt;angular-cli&lt;/a&gt; tool. After running their setup, all I had to do was configure a few components, set up my form and calculations, and apply some styles. It’s pretty barebones, but it got me to learn the basics of what AngularJS is all about, and I’m excited to be be able to use its tools in future projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sosnader.tk/grade-calc&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/grade.png&quot; alt=&quot;grade app screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/technology/2016/12/18/making-a-webapp-with-angularjs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/technology/2016/12/18/making-a-webapp-with-angularjs.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Devil is in the Detail</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To be honest, before we started working on this project, I thought that the hardest part would definitely be filming things, or maybe writing out the script to form a coherent narrative. Yet, our group finished those parts really quickly, and pretty easily. We divided our work up, got it done, reviewed each others, then recorded the narration and filmed a few scenes with a camera from the media center. All in all, a solid one day of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real trouble is coming from all the editing. First, we had some camera audio issues we didn’t know about that had to be fixed in post-production. Now, at least for me, iMovie is a bit of a pain to use. It glitches with my audio clips, cutting off pieces that I actually wanted, and randomly resizing the lengths when I add pictures or videos to a different track, for seemingly no reason. It doesn’t let me place clips where I want, instead forcing me to adhere to its random placement. The controls for several features are not nearly as granular as I would like them to be (looking at you, Ken Burns effect), and the UI seems unintuitive and hamstrung. I will admit, it’s definitely better than attempting to use something truly professional, like Adobe Premiere, but I didn’t forsee how much time the editing would take, partly because I have to figure out how everything works, and partly because just getting everything together and perfectly lined up takes lots of time. Still, though, it seems to be working out pretty well, and I’m excited to see what our final product looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue we still might run into and have to deal with is the length of our docmentary. We have a lot of info for each section, and we might run over the 10 minutes with everything we want to say. If that’s the case, we’ll have to decide what we can cut from it. Other than that, we’re doing pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2016/12/04/devil-in-the-detail.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2016/12/04/devil-in-the-detail.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rcl</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Stranger</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/stranger.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the stranger cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Stranger&lt;/em&gt; is one of those classic novels, written in 1942 by Albert Camus. I read it senior year for English class. It’s widely considered an existentialist novel, although apparently (a quick Wikipedia search tells me) Camus rejected that label (instead calling it absurdist). Regardless, it’s really interesting, and shows what one can do with a novel beyond the typical storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The novel follows the life of a French Algerian, Mersault, as he goes about his daily life. Mersault, however, is no ordinary character. The book starts with Mersault receiving word of his mother’s death, yet, Mersault hardly seems to care. This theme of uncaringness seems to follow through the entire book. Mersault only cares about the physical realities of the world around him, thinking nothing of the people, or emotions he should feel as events happen to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Camus uses this book as a vehicle for displaying his philosophy of the absurd, and he does it quite effectively. In essence, Camus is contrasting the struggle of humanity attempting to find meaning in life, yet failing to find it. Mersualt is attacked by many people throughout the book for his seemingly uncaring attitude. People simply cannot understand how he does not see the same meaning in life as they do. In this way, Mersault is an existentialist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, this book may seem like another one of those stuffy books that English teachers tout around yet turn out to be awful to read (I’m looking at you, &lt;em&gt;Scarlet Letter&lt;/em&gt;). But for some reason, this one stuck with me. The writing is beautiful to read. The novel takes an interesting angle, with one of the most unique main characters of any book I’ve read. And, like any good book should, it makes you think. It makes you ask questions. And that makes it worth it to read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/12/01/the-stranger.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/12/01/the-stranger.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The New Neediness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/loveme.gif&quot; alt=&quot;love me gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One aspect of the &lt;em&gt;The Circle&lt;/em&gt; that I think Dave Eggers utilized really well to critique modern society was his depiction of the “neediness” that people seem to have developed, the desire for attention that overwhelms Mae at points, and disgusts Mercer. It’s the relentless begging for likes, shares, pings, and responses that seems ridiculous, but has solid basis in reality. We see it many times throughout the book. Mae is pestered by people when she becomes famous to respond to all of their notes, to look at their websites, to help their children with this or that by giving them attention. Francis’s strange desires, like asking Mae to rate his “performance” also reflect this neediness. It’s mostly seen through the social and online aspect of the book. As Mercer says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now the movie stars beg people to follow their Zing feeds. They send pleading messages asking everyone to smile at them. And holy fuck, the mailing lists! Everyone’s a junk mailer. You know how I spend an hour every day? Thinking of ways to unsubscribe to mailing lists without hurting anyone’s feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This attitude is already becoming pervasive online. People will follow hundreds of others in the hopes of getting follow backs, they offer “like for like,” comment to get ratings and messages from their friends on Facebook, send snapchats out to everyone and get offended when people open and don’t respond to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t always like this, obviously. What changed? To me, it seems pretty simple. In the past, we didn’t expect people to respond and interact so much and so rapidly because we simply couldn’t. When you sent a letter you had to wait a while for a response, and even if you didn’t get one, it was possible that your letter was just lost. After the invention of the telephone, communication became easier, but if someone didn’t pick up the phone you simply had to assume they were busy. However, once smartphones and the Internet were invented, it became much harder for people to “excuse away” others behavior. You no longer could assume that someone just “didn’t see the text” because you can go and look at their social media accounts and see that they’re using their phone and just ignoring you. And although we rationally know there are many reasons why someone wouldn’t get back to you instantly (and if you think about it, you’ve done it many times yourself, often by accident), we find it hard to reconcile that idea in our head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, as always, Eggers goes too far. Yes, in today’s society, we all get a little miffed if we don’t get a response, or a like, or if we see an opened snapchat. But we get over it, because we know that in the end, it’s not a big deal. Even with the hypersociality of The Circle, it’s unrealistic that people would become &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; needy, &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; whiny, and &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; intense. The causes are the same, but the effects in real life are nowhere near the effects in the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/circle/2016/11/25/the-new-neediness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/circle/2016/11/25/the-new-neediness.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>circle</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
