<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brenden Sosnader</title>
    <description>Hi, I&#39;m Brenden Sosnader. I study computer science at Penn State University and I like to make things. This is where I show them off.
</description>
    <link>http://sosnader.tk/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sosnader.tk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 20:56:08 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 20:56:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Issue Brief</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1yELJEE1DgdKyl_TuJUx7a5Sz9w-SlGGUssQaeCAI1Aw/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Link to issue brief&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2017/03/28/issue-brief.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2017/03/28/issue-brief.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rcl</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>50 Shades of Grey</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DISCLAIMER: I have not actually read this book, however it was requested that I review a romance novel, so here it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure we all have heard of &lt;em&gt;50 Shades of Grey,&lt;/em&gt; by EL James. It’s basically a part of mainstream pop culture by now. It’s rocked the nation, sold over 125 million copies as of June 2015, and been translated into 52 languages. Two movies have been made out of it and its sequel, &lt;em&gt;50 Shades Darker&lt;/em&gt; (wow, what a creative name).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; it about this book that makes it so popular? Could it have deep, compelling prose that pulls out the intricacies of love and romance, like the classic, &lt;em&gt;The Scarlet Letter?&lt;/em&gt; Could it be that it perhaps takes a daring approach at a difficult subject, and executes a careful yet masterful exploration of BDSM? Or, maybe it’s that the people have been longing for a well written book with a strong female lead, and &lt;em&gt;50 Shades&lt;/em&gt; perfectly picks up this mantle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoiler: it’s none of these things. It’s garbage, an awfully written erotic novel based on a &lt;em&gt;Twilight&lt;/em&gt; fanfiction that has managed to capture so much attention due to it’s exploitation of one of humanity’s most basic urges – sex. The only reason this book has done so well is because it’s managed to put a mainstream face on an erotica novel. I’m not even sure how it happened, though, because the book is so poorly written. Not only that, it also portrays not a healthy, loving relationship, but one of abuse, exploitation, and cruelty. The relationship portrayed in the book is not one that any person should seek out, and by making it sound like a thrillfest, EL James is doing harm to our society’s perception of healthy sexual relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, please, don’t read this book. And if you already have, I am so sorry. I’ll leave you with a quote from the book that makes me burst out in laughter every time I read it because of how awful it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I feel the colour in my cheeks rising again. I must be the colour of The Communist Manifesto.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/comm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Communist Manifesto cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/03/22/50-shades-of-grey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/03/22/50-shades-of-grey.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Stormlight Archive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/archive.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;archive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m gonna talk about one of my favorite fantasy series by one of my favorite authors: &lt;em&gt;The Stormlight Archive,&lt;/em&gt; by Brandon Sanderson. Brandon Sanderson has been around for a while, and he basically writes books like a tank. If you’re sick of George RR Martin’s incredibly slow writing pace, then you’ll be glad to hear that Sanderson is the exact opposite. He just churns out book after book, series after series, and it’s all quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually first read Sanderson books in gradeschool–he had this series for young adults about this evil cult of librarians. It was funny and well written. About a year ago, I read through a lot of his other works, and loved it all. He’s mainly a fantasy writer, and all of his fantasy series have really cool, unique systems of magic and little quirks. He’s really good at fleshing out cool, fantastical elements in his stories. Another cool thing is that many of his stories and series are actually connected under one big universe that he calls “The Cosmere.” You can find hints and refernces to other stories and events in just about all of his books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, on to &lt;em&gt;The Stormlight Archive.&lt;/em&gt; He has another really great series, &lt;em&gt;Mistborn,&lt;/em&gt; which I also loved, but I’ll save that for another time. &lt;em&gt;The Stormlight Archive,&lt;/em&gt; is Sanderson’s first attempt at writing an epic fantasy series (like along the lines of &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;The Wheel of Time&lt;/em&gt;, which Sanderson actaully finished after the original author died). These books are really long. He plans on publishing ten books, and there’s two already out, with a third coming later this year. Unlike GRRM, I actually have faith that Sanderson will finish the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I can’t really properly describe what the world in these books is actually &lt;em&gt;like,&lt;/em&gt; because it’s pretty complicated, but I’ll send you over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Way_of_Kings#Setting&quot;&gt;Wikipedia’s&lt;/a&gt; description of the setting. There’s like magic gemstones and spirits and really cool glowing swords and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One possible downside of Sanderson that he tends to write very clean books. If you’re used to GRRM and lots of blood, sex, and cursing, you’ll be disappointed to not find any of that in Sanderson’s books. His characters don’t curse, instead opting to say things like “Storms!” where you’d expect someone to say “Fuck.” Romance is very PG and may remind you of middle school, rather than real life. But his books are always just really enjoyable to read. You get drawn in to the world, and the creative elements behind it. Sanderson is really good at worldbuilding and creating an intense and exciting story, even if his prose isn’t my personal favorite style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check him out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/03/16/the-stormlight-archive.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/03/16/the-stormlight-archive.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Reversal of the Political Parties</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know the two main political parties of today. On the one side, there’s the Republicans: staunch conservatives who favor small government, state’s rights, and big business (yes, this is an oversimplification). On the other side, there’s the Democrats: liberals who focus more on big government programming and social progressiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it wasn’t always like this. Before we get into the history of the Democratic and Republican Parties specifically, let’s take a look at the history of political parties in the United States as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;george-washington&quot;&gt;George Washington&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George Washington, our first president, wasn’t actually in any political party, technically. He actually did not like the idea of political parties, saying in his Farewell Address:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“However [political parties] may now and then answer popular ends, they are likely in the course of time and things, to become potent engines, by which cunning, ambitious, and unprincipled men will be enabled to subvert the power of the people and to usurp for themselves the reins of government, destroying afterwards the very engines which have lifted them to unjust dominion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Perhaps even more pertient in our present political climate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyway, that didn’t last long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;federalist-party&quot;&gt;Federalist Party&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technically, the Federalist Party could be considered the party of Washington. Its ideas were centered around the concept of federalism, i.e. a strong central government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anti-federalist-party&quot;&gt;Anti-Federalist Party&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self explanatory, basically. These guys sprung up right around 1800 and focused more on the common people and their right for representation. They were renamed the Republican Party, and then the Democratic-Republican Party. In the 1810s, the Federalist Party fell apart. The Democratic Republican Party split into different factions. Around the time of Andrew Jackson’s presidency, they were renamed simply the Democratic Party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whig-party&quot;&gt;Whig Party&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A different faction of the Democratic Republican Party formed the Whig Party.  The Whig Party is important in the formation of the Republican Party because the Republican Party continued many of the ideas of the Whig Party, mainly, big government involvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;democratic-and-republican-parties&quot;&gt;Democratic and Republican Parties&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the timeline where we can begin discussing these two parties and how they changed starts right around the Civil War. The Republican Party at the time, was the “party of Lincoln,” and as such, promoted forward-thinking ideas like freedom of slavery, voting rights for black men, and big government. The Democratic Party at the time was more traditional–it wasn’t new and fresh like the Republican Party, and it focused more on things like state’s rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Civil War, the Republican Party had multiple factions–some with more progressive economic ideas, and some with more conservative ideas. This will be important later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right before 1900, with William Jennings Bryan being the Democratic Party’s presidental candidate, the party shifted a bit more to the progressive side. WJB incorporated the Populist Party under the Democratic Party, which gave it a more economically left angle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, remember how the Republican Party had those two factions? In 1912 Teddy Roosevelt runs under the Progressive Party, not the Republican Party, breaking away that progressive faction and leaving only the conservative behind. Franklin Roosevelt in the 1930s adopted Progressive Party platforms into the Democratic coalition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major shift comes in the 1960s with Lyndon B Johnson. Civil Rights become part of the Democratic Platform, and alienates many southern white voters. At this time, the Republican Party begins implementing the “Southern strategy,” where they appealed to southern, racist, white voters who were alienated by the Democratic Party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, at this point, we can generally see the political parties having the same alignments as they do today. The Democratic Party embraced many progressive ideals, both economic and social. The Republican Party ended up losing its progressive economic wing and, to get more votes, became more socially conservative. However, the parties were still not super polarized at this point. You could find conservative democrats and liberal republicans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrast that with today’s political climate, and you see extreme polarization on both sides. There’s barely ever any compromise, and it’s frankly vicious to watch. The reasons for this, in my opinion, are largely due to the polarization that occurred during the Obama presidency. I touched on that in my previous post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s the general gist of it. I think we’re due for a reorganization of splitting of either or both of the two parties soon. The polarization is too extreme, and there’s infighting in the parties. We’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.quora.com/Is-it-true-that-Democrats-used-to-be-the-conservative-party-and-Republicans-used-to-be-the-progressive-party
https://tedtheeconomist.wordpress.com/2015/07/06/when-exactly-did-the-political-paradigm-shift-happen/comment-page-1/
http://www.government-and-constitution.org/history-us-political-parties/timeline-us-political-parties.htm&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/civic-issues/2017/03/15/reversal-political-parties.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/civic-issues/2017/03/15/reversal-political-parties.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>civic-issues</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Discworld</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/disc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;discworld&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Discworld&lt;/em&gt; is not one book, but a series of books by the English author Terry Pratchett. It’s one of my all time favorite series. Terry Pratchett is, unfortunately, deceased, but before he went, he wrote 40 of these books, so he did pretty well for himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind the Discworld universe is that, you guessed it, the world is a disc. The disc rests atop four elephants, which are standing on a giant turtle which floats through space. Yeah. Very realistic. It’s a fantasy world, with magic and all sorts of other crazy things. It’s kind of disengenuous to call Discworld a series, though. It’s more like a large collection of books all in the same universe, with different recurring people and areas and a (kind of loose) overall story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s actually no need to read any of the stories in any particular order. I personally read them all in their published order, but that’s not necessary. There’s a few infographics online outlining good ways to start, and the different story arcs and plotlines. In general, there’s four main groups of people to look out for. There’s Rincewind, who’s a magician, the Witches, who are witches (duh), Death (I don’t have to explain), and The Watch. The Watch follows the lives of the city watchmen in Discworld’s twin cities, Ankh Morpork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/reading.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;reading order&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I like these books so much is not just because they’re good fantasy books (and I really like fantasy), but because they’re actually incredibly funny. If you’ve ever read &lt;em&gt;The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy,&lt;/em&gt; you’ll know exactly the type of humor I’m talking about. It’s that dry British wit that comes out in fantastic ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave you with some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/donnad/discworld-quotes-about-life-the-universe-and-everything&quot;&gt;best quotes&lt;/a&gt; from the books.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/03/02/discworld.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/03/02/discworld.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Naked Economics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we’re gonna take a different track than the normal fiction books I’ve been writing about. Instead, I’m gonna talk about a book that I sincerely believe everyone should read for the purpose of their own education. It’s called &lt;em&gt;Naked Economics&lt;/em&gt;, by Charles Wheelan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, you might be horrified at the prospect of reading a book about Econ. Economics gets a bad rap as a terrible subject, but it can actually be very interesting, if approached right. It’s also incredibly important (in my opinion) for everyone to have a basic grasp of economics, because, after all, money is what makes the world go round. We deal with and hear about economic issues every day of our live, yet many people just don’t understand what’s going on. And it’s not entirely their fault–it’s true that economics can be a dense and inaccessible topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this book is not that. It’s easy to read, enjoyable, and has great explanations on a variety of topics related to economics. It looks at all sorts of situations around the world and explains the economics behind them. My eyes were opened to a lot of new perspectives and things I hadn’t even thought about. While this won’t make you an expert, it will definitely help explain a bit of what goes on in the world around you, at least economically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I really do think everyone should read this book. In an ideal world, everyone would be able to take several in-depth economics classes to get a better, fuller understanding of the topic, but this book is a good start. Definitely think about checking it out if you’re in the mood for a nonfiction book and for some self edification. Also, if you really want, you can read his follow up book: &lt;em&gt;Naked Statistics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/02/23/naked-economics.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/02/23/naked-economics.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deliberation Reflection</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My experience at a deliberation was very positive. On Monday, I went to a deliberation on sexual assault in college in a place called “CommonPlace.” It was super cozy, with couches and futons galore. This was in stark contrast to our own deliberation, which was on the third floor of a church in a bleak and forboding space. Regardless, we sat down, and the deliberation began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audience was completely comprised of college students. I wasn’t exactly surpised by that, but I was kind of hoping to see more adults taking part. There was only one student &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in an RCL class there, which also was not that surprising, but again, I was kind of hoping for a greater variety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sexual assalt is a delicate topic, and I was worried that this group might make a few slip ups in their explanaiton and introduction to the topic. However, I thought they did a pretty good job of explaining the issue and kicking off the discussion. Another thing I was worried about was that nobody would want to participate. That wasn’t the case as well. Everyone had a lot to say, and a lot to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group did really well with their amount of questions, and finding good follow up questions to keep the conversation going. I think that’s one of the hardest parts of completing a successful deliberation, because when the discussion dies down, it gets &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; awkward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main approaches that we discussed involved three different things: approaching sexaul assault education at a younger level, providing more education and support at the university level, or increasing punishments and awareness of punishments. I think most people, myself included, thought the best approach would involve more education at a younger level. However, there’s definitely issues with implementing that, for instance, in areas (like the SOUTH) where this type of sexual education doesn’t fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second approach involved better education in the university setting. We all agreed that the Penn State programs like SAFE/AWARE aren’t that effective because people who don’t care can just ignore them. Also, programs that other universities have aren’t that effective either because they’re ususally opt-in, and those who are most likely to opt in are the ones least likely to commit sexual assualt in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final approach involved increasing punishments and increasing awareness of punishments in an attempt to deter would-be assualters. A really good point was brought up that I hadn’t thought of before– that increasing punishments might actually lead to &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; reporting by victims. Often, sexual assault attackers are known to the victim, and unfortunately, victims feel bad sometimes about “turning in” their attacker to face punishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the big things I thought was important to discuss was how to properly educate people on the concept of consent. If everyone had a very clear, very strong defintion of consent, I think it would help this issue greatly. There are a lot of shitty people out there who do things and don’t think they’re doing anything wrong. However, if we had a really clear concept of consent firmly ingrained in everyone’s mind that it would help shame people into not doing these sorts of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I thought it was a really good deliberation with a lot of productive discussion that led to me thinking about some things I hadn’t thought about before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2017/02/23/deliberation-reflection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2017/02/23/deliberation-reflection.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rcl</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Slaughterhouse-Five</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/house.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;slaughterhouse five&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slaughterhouse-Five, by Kurt Vonnegut, is a pretty cool book that I read last summer. I’m pretty sure it’s known as one of those “classic” books that everyone should read. And I’m not gonna lie, it’s a good book. It covers a fictional story about Billy Pilgrim, a chaplain’s assistant in World War II. It’s an anti war novel, so if you’ve read anything like &lt;em&gt;For Whom the Bell Tolls&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Catch-22&lt;/em&gt;, you know the type. It’s partially based off of Vonnegut’s own experiences during World War II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is pretty good, and pretty interesting writing style. The story is told by an unreliable narrator who takes you through the story in a series of flashbacks. There’s some pretty crazy stuff involving aliens (or does it?) and overall the gritty tone accurately represents how World War II probably was for Vonnegut. The style and the confusing narrative only serve to further reinforce the idea of the confusion and terror felt while at war. I’ll admit, I’m still not entirely sure of the purpose of the aliens tangent, but maybe someone else more well versed with the book could explain it to me sometime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always thought that anti-war novels are very important to have and to be shared. Too often it seems like war and violence is romanticized, and the terrible parts are glossed over in favor of excitement and action. We need books like these from those who have actually experienced war to remind us what it’s like. And I think this format is better than a  lecture on the topic, because it’s more entertaining and engaging. The skill of the writer allows us to feel more strongly about the horrible things happening in the book, in a way a lecture or documentary perhaps couldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leave you with a quote (supposedly) from Robert E Lee:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is well that war is so terrible — lest we should grow too fond of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/02/15/slaughterhouse-five.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/02/15/slaughterhouse-five.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maze Runner</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/maze.png&quot; alt=&quot;maze runner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maze Runner&lt;/em&gt;, by James Dashner, is one of those ~classic~ young adult, dystopian science fiction novels that have been all the rage for the past decade. You may have heard about the movie that was made from it. The movie was trash. But the book wasn’t bad. I really enjoyed it, and even reread it a few times. I think that even if a writer follows a stereotypical genre, or doesn’t use much complexity in their writing, a book can still be just fun to read. This book was fun to read because of the concept behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, children are stuck in a massive underground labrynth. There’s a lot of mystery behind the whole purpose behind any of it. They have to try to figure out a way out, while avoiding the Maze’s many dangers. The mystery of the Maze, and the motivations behind it, make up a large part of the book. It’s a really interesting concept. Much like everyone liked The Hunger Games because of its unique concept, the same applies here. I wouldn’t go into this book expecting much, but it’s a fun and quick read if you’re looking for a dystopian future sci fi fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to warn you though, do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; try reading any of the other sequels to this book. You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt;, if you really want to, but they just got extremely weird and really bad. Some crazy stuff goes down, and I just was not enjoying it. James Dashner is a good writer, but I think he overtaxed himself here. Still, though, the first book is good, and also is another book which is better than its movie. I don’t think I’ve seen any movies that were better than their books. If you have I’d love to hear about them. That’s all for this week!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/02/08/maze-runner.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2017/02/08/maze-runner.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Obamacare and Partisanship</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Affordable Care Act, or as it’s better known, Obamacare, has been a sharply partisan issue since the moment it was conceived. One would think that on the topic of healthcare, both sides of the aisle could come together to find a solution good for the entirety of America, however, that has not been the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of Obamacare begins on the campaign trail. Obama promises a solution to rising healthcare costs, saying, “On health care reform, the American people are too often offered two extremes — government-run health care with higher taxes or letting the insurance companies operate without rules. … I believe both of these extremes are wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obama, from the very start of his first term, was committed to making some form of healthcare reform happen. He began discussions, pushed Congress to start drafting up plans, and made it one of his priorities. It’s important to note that Obama took a different approach than Bill Clinton had before him. Bill Clinton had formed a plan of his own, and then presented it to Congress. Obama knew that he had to let Congress work out something that could actually get passed. Obama also made sure he had the support of some major players in the healthcare industry, something else that was needed. Most importantly, Obama tried, from the very beginning, to get Republican support for the bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, that goal simply was not happening. In 2009, the healthcare bill passed through the House (where Democrats had a supermajority) with only a singular Republican vote. It would find a much more difficult time getting through the Senate. In the Senate, the so-called “Gang of Six” formed, contrived of three Democrats and three Republicans, who were supposed to build a bill that would be agreeable for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the basis of the plan discussed at this point was actually a Republican healthcare plan from the 90s. It was not a single-payer system, which would be a firmly Democratic and liberal system. It still involved the insurance companies and it still had an individual mandate. However, it was certainly a step in the right direction. Obama was trying to make real compromise here, along with the Democratic Congresspeople.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the negotiations were a sham. Mitch McConnell, leader of the Senate Republicans, had already told his members that they could not reach a deal with the Democrats, and that none of them would be voting for any sort of healthcare reform bill. (Sidenote: I can’t be unbiased here. Mitch McConnell is a partisan hack. He represents everything that is wrong with the Republican party, and partisan politics as a whole. His obstructionism of the past eight years, and his, frankly, imbecilic manner of running the Senate, is pathetic. I can’t stand anything about the man.) The negotiations went on for a little while more, and then fell apart. Eventually, when brought to a vote, every single Democrat voted for, while every Republican voted against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest is history. Obamacare went to the Supreme Court, and was upheld. Due to the controversy, Republicans were able to make sweeping gains in the House in 2010, which, coupled with the census, lead to the redistricting and gerrymandering I talked about last article. Republicans would spend the next eight years blocking anything and everything that even had a faint whiff of Obama on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/aca.png&quot; alt=&quot;affordable care act&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what partisanship does to America. An originally Republican plan gets decried by Republicans simply because Democrats were the ones pushing for it. Healthcare reform, something everyone needed at the time, was crippled by the partisanship of Congress. People hated Obamacare simply because of the name Obama. I remember watching a video clip of people being asked if they preferred the Affordable Care Act over Obamacare. Many said yes, having no idea they were the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even now, partisanship blinds citizens from making rational decisions about the policies their government passes. There are thousands of Republican Trump supporters who are on Obamacare, who don’t want it to go away. If you look on Twitter, you can see them complaining to Trump about repealing it. They didn’t realize what they voted for, and now they regret it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be funny, if it weren’t so sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2015/06/25/from-the-very-start-sharp-partisan-divisions-over-obamacare/
https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2015/07/the-real-story-of-obamacares-birth/397742/
http://affordablehealthca.com/timeline-obamacare/&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/civic-issues/2017/02/07/obamacare.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/civic-issues/2017/02/07/obamacare.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>civic-issues</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
