<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brenden Sosnader</title>
    <description>Hi, I&#39;m Brenden Sosnader. I study computer science at Penn State University and I like to make things. This is where I show them off.
</description>
    <link>http://sosnader.tk/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sosnader.tk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 11:33:23 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 11:33:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Song of Ice and Fire</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/ice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;map of westeros&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although George R.R. Martin’s &lt;em&gt;A Song of Ice and Fire&lt;/em&gt; is technically a series, not a single book, I can’t talk about one book without talking about them all. And believe me, every single one of these books is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure all of you have heard of (or watched) HBO’s adaptation of this series. If you’ve watched the show, then you know how amazing the story is. If not, then you probably have a general idea of what it’s like– dragons, swordfights, and more. But the books (and the show) are so much more than that. George manages to weave so many intricate plots together without giving away any clear idea of what will happen in the end. Also, he has no qualms about killing off important characters, so there’s none of that “plot armor” that so many main characters seem to have. Everyone is in danger, everyone has plans, and there’s no clear idea of who will emerge on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, George creates a complex, realistic world (well, realistic enough for fantasy) which its characters populate and exist with their own different cultures and traditions. One of the most important parts of any good fantasy novel is the world it’s in, and George’s world is interesting, engaging, and plain cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book’s are all behemoths, requriring a lot of invested time to read. They draw you in, though, and keep you engaged. Even the lenghtly descriptions of feasts were somehow still enjoyable to read. However, if you haven’t read or watched anything yet, fair warning– George might die before finishing the last two (or maybe even three) books. Then it’d be up to the show to finish it off. However, the show and the book have differences, and have branched off a little bit. So we may never know exactly how George plans to end it. Still, it’s more than worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/11/16/a-song-of-ice-and-fire.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/11/16/a-song-of-ice-and-fire.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/dont-panic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;don&#39;t panic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past few weeks, I’ve been doing books that I think speak to everyone–books that I think everyone would enjoy reading and that apply to all of our lives. And although I enjoy reading those sorts of books, I’d be lying if I said they’re the majority of books I read. In reality, I mostly read fantasy and sci-fi. And although you may not enjoy these books as well, I feel like it’d be wrong if I didn’t give them fair representation. So in the coming weeks I’ll probably be doing more of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, &lt;em&gt;The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; is a true classic, and something anyone can enjoy–as long as they like dry British humor. Written by Douglas Adams, this book is packed full of clever wit and exotic characters. It follows the life of the most boring and mundane British person ever, Arthur Dent, as he finds himself suddenly teleported out into space right before the destruction of Earth by his friend Ford Prefect, who’s actually an alien.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, though, it gets a lot weirder. You’ll be introduced to the perils of Vogon poetry, a man with two heads and a depressed android, and the importance of always having your towel. It’s definitely not for everyone, but the humor is out of this world (see what I did there), including clever phrases such as this one, describing teleportation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s unpleasantly like being drunk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What’s so unpleasant about being drunk?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You ask a glass of water.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole book is like this, and it’s a wild ride that I never find myself tired of reading. If you’re into this genre, and somehow haven’t read it yet, I highly recommend checking it out. There’s four other books after it, all just as funny, and even a sixth written after he died by another author.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/10/25/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/10/25/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Circle&#39;s Paradigm Shift</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this section of &lt;em&gt;The Circle,&lt;/em&gt; we get to see the paradigm shift that the book has been hinting at start hitting in full swing. Politicians are pressured into going transparent, more and more people are becoming connected, and there is an increasing pressure on Mae and others to respond, interact, and share. It’s the culmination of what Eggers fears will happen to our own society, and it’s a drastic change that affects everyone’s lives and makes the world different–the definition of a paradigm shift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we see is that sharing, whether willing or unwilling, becomes the new mantra of living. If one isn’t sharing, then one isn’t truly living, this new society seems to say. That’s different from how The Circle operated before, and it’s certainly different from our own society. Before this shift, although sharing was heavily pressured, it was not at the level it is after Mae’s transparency. Politicans are heavily pressured into going transparent, Mae’s parents are told they must uncover their cameras, and Mae is attacked by people who get offended when she doesn’t instantly get back to them and share and connect with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can see very obviously the negative repurcussions of this shift. Because Eggers is argueing against this way of life, he heavily emphasizes and exhibits them. For instance, Mae’s parents getting caught “in the act” is one such negative side effect. As we all have discussed before, some things are just meant to be private. Later, Mae is overwhelmed by all the people insisting to have her attention, and breaks down on the inside. Humans, although social creatures, are not built to handle the amount of interaction displayed in this section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should amend my previous statement now, come to think of it. The paradigm shift is almost there, but it’s not complete. I think the true paradigm shift will come when The Circle is “closed.” It’s not directly said what that means, but it’s clear it’s some sort of major change or completion. This completion will be the true paradigm shift. It will be when everyone is sharing everything, all connected, all interacting, with no secrets. It sounds like it could be alluring, in a way. I mean, if we are all connected to one another, truly and fully, we could form some sort of utopian society where there is no hate, crime, or fear, because everyone understands everyone else. Yet, we see very clearly that it could never work. For one, there are too many people like Mercer, who would reject the system. Second, as I explained before, humans are not built for that and could not withstand the constant pressure. Finally, also as I’ve argued before, some things are meant to be private and should stay that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I think this paradigm shift could ever occur in our society? No. I think Eggers goes too far and is too drastic with his shift. It’s not really believable or realistic. It’s one of the major flaws of &lt;em&gt;The Circle&lt;/em&gt;–it’s just too obvious and over the top in the point that it’s making. Nevertheless, the shift is clearly present in this section, and is nearing completion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/circle/2016/10/23/circle-paradigm-shift.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/circle/2016/10/23/circle-paradigm-shift.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>circle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Perks of Being a Wallflower</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/wallflower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;cover&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you guys have heard of &lt;em&gt;The Perks of Being a Wallflower&lt;/em&gt;, either from the popular movie or from the book it was based off of. I remember seeing trailers for the movie but never really looking into it, thinking it wasn’t my kind of movie. I had no idea it was originally a book until a friend of mine insisted that I read it. Apparently I was “four years too late” (the book’s about a freshman in high school) but I figured I could still enjoy it. He told me “if you can, read it in one sitting.” So I did. I read it over the weekend, without any expectations or understanding of what it was about going in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not what I was expecting at all, but it was amazing. If you don’t know, the story follows a boy, Charlie, as he enters high school and completes his freshman year. Charlie is not okay. He has faced many unfortunate circumstances, is a bit socially awkward, and can’t really seem to figure out his place in the world. Charlie’s freshman year is full of twists and turns, and ups and downs, and through it all, we always see Charlie being as genuine and kind as always. He’s incredibly selfless, but has trouble taking care of himself. The book is intense, touching on very rough topics. It’s very interesting to see the way these topics are viewed through the lense of a teenage boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s so much packed into the book for its length, and to be honest, it made me tear up multiple times. There are some passages that sort of bite right into your core, unveiling things you maybe didn’t really want to think about before. If you get the chance, read it, and read it in one sitting. It’s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/10/17/perks-of-being-a-wallflower.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/10/17/perks-of-being-a-wallflower.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Paradigm Shift</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The paradigm shift that I think I would most likely choose for this assignment actually comes from another class I’m taking– Astro 5. In astronomy, there was a drastic paradigm shift around the time of Galileo and Keplar from a geocentric model of the universe to a heliocentric model. Basically, the world changed from believing that the universe rotated around the Earth to believing that the Earth rotated around the Sun. This change actually had drastic effects not only for the scientific community but also philosophically and religiously. There was tons of controversy about this change and it affected many things in many different sciences and teachings. I think it would be a really interesting topic to delve deep into, because today, we all know how the Solar System works, but back then, the “heavens” were thought of far differently than we think of them now. So I’m not really gonna put up another choice unless you guys really think this is a bad one, because I’m pretty set on this idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keywords: astronomy, heliocentrism, geocentrism, solar system, Copernicus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite TED talk is one by Glenn Greenwald entitled &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/glenn_greenwald_why_privacy_matters&quot;&gt;Why Privacy Matters&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a discussion of why, in this digital age, our privacy still should matter to us. I actually used quotes from it when I was writing my Schreyer admission essay on the topic, and I think it’s especially pertinent to us given our reading of &lt;em&gt;The Circle.&lt;/em&gt; It’s definitely interesting to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2016/10/13/paradigm-shift.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2016/10/13/paradigm-shift.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rcl</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Giver</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/giver.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the giver cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Giver&lt;/em&gt;, by Lois Lowry is a book that many of us probably had to read for school at some point in our lives. I actually didn’t, and only recently read it. It’s more of a book for people a little bit younger than me, but I still found it enjoyable, and the ideas it explored made me think. We actually discussed it (well, the movie) in our AP Psychology class that year, and after I read The Circle, and especially after I responded to this week’s prompt about &lt;em&gt;The Circle&lt;/em&gt;, I thought of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book takes place in a futuristic society where all pain, fear, war, and hatred is eliminated. Everyone and everything is bascially the same. The people are uniform and conform to what the leaders ask for. The plot revolves around a boy, Jonas, who is chosen to be the society’s next “giver.” The concept of the giver is very intriguing, and what Jonas struggles with is the main theme of the story. Like I have with all the previous books, I won’t give much away, but if you haven’t already read it, it’s worth the read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’d really like to talk about the society that’s set up in &lt;em&gt;The Giver.&lt;/em&gt; The conformity of the people clearly leads to less pain and hate, but is it worth it? That question is emphasized in the book, and I think it’s important to consider. In &lt;em&gt;The Circle&lt;/em&gt;, too, the goal is to eliminate things like crime, corruption, and hatred by exposing everyone to everything and controlling it all. Is it worth the loss of rights, the lost of individuality, and the loss of freedom? Eggers clearly thinks not, but what do you think? Really consider it. I mean, a world without crime is unimaginable. A goal that would be amazing to reach. But what are we willing to give up to get it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/10/06/the-giver.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/10/06/the-giver.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>*The Circle* and Transparency</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll be responding to prompt 2, and discussing The Circle’s three mantras: “Secrets are Lies,” “Sharing is Caring, “ and “Privacy is Theft.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although these mantras may seem very tempting (and I’ll explain why they might be tempting later), I firmly believe that they are unequivocally wrong and destructive to society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the first one, “Secrets are Lies.” Bailey says that secrets “fester” within somone until they are shared and put out in the open, and that hiding a secret from someone is the same thing as lying to them. But, no matter how idealistic one may try to be, one must realize that secrets have a necessary place in society. I’m not talking about hiding from your spouse that you cheated on them. It’s things like your feelings about someone or something that you withold, not out of malice, but out of tact. Sometimes it’s best to keep your mouth shut, either because you know that what you’ll say will cause unnecessary strife, or because, like all humans, you know you’re fallible and may change your mind. It’s better to be cautious and keep your thoughts to yourself for some topics until you get more information or have more time to consider the consequences of sharing a secret. Sometimes people say things in confidentiality because they know what they tell you might not be “good,” but because they still need your advice and help. By forcing people to not have secrets about anything, we’d be living in a world without tact and without the ability to treat delicate matters with the cautiousness and confidentiality they deserve. Relationships would be ruined by minor things that would never become an issue otherwise. Sometimes one needs to keep something to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to “Sharing is Caring.” This one is very similar to the above one. Things don’t need to be shared, especially if they’re linked to highly emotional topics, like an illness. Bailey says that these types of things need to be “demystified” and moved away from shame. But people don’t withhold from sharing things just because they’re ashamed. They don’t share them because they simply think that other people don’t need to know. In reality, most people do not need to know at all about certain illnesses or other personal matters. It’s not about “demystifing” those things, it’s just a matter of only letting those who actually deserve to know and care to know about personal matters. On the topic of Mae’s kayaking, and not wanting to share her experience (and later breaking the law and wanting to hide it), it’s silly to argue that not sharing all of one’s experiences is wrong. Nobody is entitled to your experiences. They’re yours. That’s what makes them special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we have “Privacy is Theft.” Bailey makes the argument that without privacy, people would never do bad things, because they’d never even have a chocie to do anything due to not having any privacy. That idea is incredibly dangerous. Although it’s true that when people are aware that they’re being watched they’re less likely to commit crimes, it’s also true that when a society has a feeling of being watched or controlled, they moderate their actions to be conformist and subdued. We’d have no protests about injustices, no great thinkers standing up to speak new ideas, and no societal change. When people are forced to conform because they feel like they’re always being watched and judged, we lose our sense of individuality and thus lose a little bit of our humanity. We are not a herd to be controlled. Privacy is essential for the freedom of expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ideas may seem tantilizing, because, as Bailey argues, they could lead to less crime, a better ability to experience interesting and exciting things, and perhaps a more accepting and understanding society on certain issues, the negatives and conformity far outweigh the positives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/circle/2016/10/06/the-circle-and-transparency.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/circle/2016/10/06/the-circle-and-transparency.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>circle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Essay &amp; Speech Revisions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a few revisions I’m going to be making to my rhetorical artifact essay and speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my speech, I’m keeping the structure and format the same, but to aid in my presentation, I’ll be showing quotes overlaid over pictures to supplement my disucssion of the rhetorical devices used in the speech. I think that having quotes displayed will be better than me reading the quotes, and having topical photos beneath them will help draw attention and make them less boring. I also changed my introduction to be from a soldier’s perspective to make it more relatable and exciting to start off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my essay, I’ll do a few things. The general gist of the essay is that it’s comparing two speeches, given by Eisenhower and Stalin. Originally, my thesis was just about how the speeches were similar with a few differences. I’m gonna expand it to more prominently point out how typically one does not associate Eisenhower and Stalin to be similar people, but rhetorically, they were on the same page. That will add depth to the essay and make it more of a compelling read. I’ll also add in more evidence in the form of quotes, and analyze those pieces of evidence and how they contribute to the overall topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than those few things, I should be good!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2016/09/27/essay-and-speech-revisions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2016/09/27/essay-and-speech-revisions.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rcl</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Road</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/road.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cover of The Road&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Road&lt;/em&gt;, by Cormac McCarthy, was another one of those English books that I was assigned senior year that I wasn’t too sure that I’d like. It was the last book of the year, assigned after the AP test, and I was kind of thinking to myself, “do I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; have to read this?” I had been looking forward to doing absolutely nothing in my classes after the AP tests. Athough my English teacher was one of my favorite teachers of all time, I really wasn’t liking his insistence on having a discussion on a book that I didn’t even know that I’d like during the last week of school. But I read it, because I actually like reading. It was more than worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Road&lt;/em&gt; is set in a post-apocalyptic America where basically nothing is recognizable. The entire landscape is grey and ashen. There is no life. The story revolves around a man and a boy, father and son. McCarthy’s writing is sparse, like the landscape, but one thing is incredibly vibrant: the strength of the father’s love for the boy. The father’s main focus is protecting and caring for his son. The story begins with a flashback that cuts to the core of the theme of the book that unfolds in the next pages. It’s an easy read, but the emotional impact of the story leaves a lasting effect on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a long reading list, though, I would recommend waiting to read this book for a while. If you decide to have kids, wait until after that. My English teacher said that he read the book several times in his life–a few times before he was a father, and a few after. He said that the impact that the book had on him quadrupled after he became a father, because of the way the parent-child relationship is portrayed in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or just read it now. It’s a good book regardless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/09/26/the-road.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/09/26/the-road.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Heartbreaking Work of Staggering Genius</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/eggers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my favorite book. If you’re looking for something to read, read this. You won’t regret it. It’s a visceral gut punch of a novel, a splash of cold water to the face that fills you with emotions—sadness, anger, joy—but often also with laughter. It’s unlike almost any other book I’ve read and it’s one of the few books that practically forced me to read it in one sitting (it’s over 400 pages—not an easy task). I don’t even know where to begin. The book overwhelmed me, tore me apart, and made me think differently about what literature can do. I don’t really know why it affected me so much. Maybe it was because of what was happening in my life when I read it. Or maybe it’s just that damn good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I should tell you what it’s about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Dave Eggers (yes, &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; Dave Eggers), &lt;em&gt;A Heartbreaking Work of Staggering Genius&lt;/em&gt; starts out with an account of both Eggers’ parents’ declines and eventual deaths from cancer. Eggers must raise his younger brother, Toph, on his own while navigating through the daunting landscape of his young adult (early 20s) life. They travel across the country, and Eggers’ desire to explore his life and struggles with himself clash with his need to protect and raise Toph. You can feel the intensity of the emotions pouring through the pages—he writes furiously, sometimes speaking directly to the reader, sometimes blurring the line between reality and the imaginary to get his message across. It’s a wonder of postmodern writing, a stream-of-consciousness directly from Eggers brain, showing you his pain, his fears, and his desires. It’s a portrait of one human’s existence which is so different than most of ours, yet incredibly relatable. It will make your heart flare and your eyes tear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s so much packed into this book. Please just read it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/09/19/a-heartbreaking-work-of-staggering-genius.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/09/19/a-heartbreaking-work-of-staggering-genius.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
