<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brenden Sosnader</title>
    <description>Hi, I&#39;m Brenden Sosnader. I study computer science at Penn State University and I like to make things. This is where I show them off.
</description>
    <link>http://sosnader.tk/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://sosnader.tk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 16:25:12 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 16:25:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Response to Zadie Smith</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook is a superficial timewaster. I know this fact, and I think the majority of my generation also knows it. The irony of Smith’s critique of Facebook is that she assumes the primary victims are the generation “below” her, those of Zuckerberg’s age and younger, when in reality, Facebook is evermore becoming a tool for those of her own generation. I can’t remember the last time I made a list of interests, or posted a status update, or even scrolled through my newsfeed. I sometimes update my profile picture, but that’s just a matter of staying current. For me, Facebook is useful for messaging people (usually about school) when I don’t have their phone number. Or, I use it to join groups (again, mostly related school) to get updates about events or to ask questions. I may be in the minority, but my feeling is that Smith’s analyzation of Facebook and its users is a bit dated. The article was written in 2010, and while many of the things written were probably true then, six years later, Facebook is a bit different. It’s now my dad that posts statuses that gain dozens of likes, comments, and shares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving past the shifting of the Facebook user landscape, I entirely agree with Smith’s characterization of those who &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; still use Facebook, and, to an extent, other social media and her dissection of the birth and purpose of Facebook. I watched the Social Network, and, while I enjoyed it thoroughly, the real Mark Zuckerberg is not Aaron Sorkin’s Mark Zuckerberg. Smith hits the nail on the head with her description: “Controlled but dull, bright and clean but uniformly plain, nonideological, affectless.” That’s the sense you get when you visit a Facebook profile that actually has been fleshed out in the full “Zuckerberg” way. A neat list of interests. Selected favorite photos. Maybe even a short bio. It’s false; it doesn’t tell you if you’d like this person in real life. I crave authenticity in relationships. The “phony” online personas that people portray, whether it be selected pictures on Instagram or curated views on Facebook, don’t appeal to me. The best connections are made in person, intimately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, on to The Circle. It’s obvious that Eggers is setting up The Circle to be a hyperbolic expansion of Facebook, and Instagram, and Snapchat, and any other social media, a juggernaut expanded beyond control or boundary. Yet, it’s not too far from being accurate. Much like you can misinterpret what someone is like based on what they’ve “liked” on Facebook, Mae is shoehorned into a Portugal group simply based on years-old pictures. The way Mae obsessively increases her PartiRank reminded me of certain people I’ve seen mindlessly tapping through 30-40 Snapchats, sending the exact same bored face in response. It’s connection without substance, and it’s what Eggers and Smith warn against. Zuckerberg simply wants “connection,” but if the connections are weak, then they’re meaningless. I get the feeling that Eggers is in agreement with me about the best way to make connections—in personal, intimate settings. Mae is most drawn to those she meets in those situations—Kalden and Francis—and we are most drawn to Mae when she’s kayaking because we get to see her at one of her most private moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s this intimacy that The Circle and Facebook are really trying to create between people. We see this idea when Mae is chastized for not wanting to share &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; her experiences with other people, and in Facebook’s efforts to allow people to share more, and more. In The Circle’s case, it’s nefarious, while I tend to think (perhaps naively) that Facebook is more, just, optimistic. Regardless, it’s an impossible task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m afraid I may have been too harsh on social media. It’s a great tool for easily rekindling past connections, or to just have fun and waste time. Humans don’t have to be deep and introspective &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt;. We’re allowed to sometimes be superficial, to just send a funny face to a friend, or to share a picture because we think we look cute in it. It’s when this attitude consumes our life, like it rapidly is doing to Mae, that it becomes an issue. It’s when young, impressionable people start to believe the harsh comments on their posts, or when people begin to base their self-validation on how many likes their photo gets, that we need to reach out and let those people know there’s more to life than what’s on the screen. Social media can be fun and harmless, but we need to stay pragmatic about where its limits are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think Smith is too scathing of Facebook. It doesn’t have to be a zero sum game. We can have great, personal relationships that are also sustained and expanded through social media. While the overwhelming nature of The Circle looks scary, I doubt we’ll go that far, as long as we remember that people exist in real life too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’ve gotta go now, I have some Snapchats to respond to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/circle/2016/09/18/response-to-zadie-smith.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/circle/2016/09/18/response-to-zadie-smith.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>circle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Last Lecture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/lecture.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Last Lecture cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another week has gone by, and it’s time to review another one of my favorite books: &lt;em&gt;The Last Lecture&lt;/em&gt;, by Randy Pausch. &lt;em&gt;The Last Lecture&lt;/em&gt; is a book of lessons and stories written by Dr. Pausch, a professor of computer science at Carnegie Mellon Universrity, after he was diagnosed with terminal pancreatic cancer. It originally started out as a lecture, titled “Really Achieving Your Childhood Dreams.” There had been a movement going around in academia where top professors would deliver a “last lecture,” i.e. what they would say if it was their last chance to impart some message to the world. In Pausch’s case, it really was one of his final chances, as he was not expected to live longer than a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lecture went over incredibly well, and many of his friends and colleagues and students were there to listen and cheer him on. Pausch decided to write a book further expanding the topic so that his kids would have something from which to learn his beliefs, thoughts, and experiences when they grew up. The book is separated into three major topics. First, Pausch goes over all of his childhood dreams, like being a Disney Imagineer, being in zero gravity, or being Captain Kirk. Then, he goes into actually acheiveing those dreams (he actually achieves more of them than you would think!). He then goes on to discuss what he feels is an incredibly important thing—enabling the dreams of others. Finally, he discusses lessons he’s learned over his lifetime and has some direct messages to his kids for when they are old enough to read the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved this book. The messages it contains are simple, but meaningful. The whole concept of a man writing a book for his kids to read after his death really touched me and added so much emotional impact to every sentence I read. I’d like to close off with one of my favorite quotes from the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s not about how to achieve your dreams, it’s about how to lead your life, … If you lead your life the right way, the karma will take care of itself, the dreams will come to you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/09/12/the-last-lecture.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/09/12/the-last-lecture.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Civic Artifact Speech Outline</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduction
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Indroduce D-Day, talk about the odds that the Allied soldiers faced&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Talk about how important the invasion was, how everything hung in the balance&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Soldiers would have been nervous&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Need to somehow motivate them and excite them with one short speech&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Introduce Eisenhower and his speech&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;He needs to find the perfect words&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Thesis:
  - Eisenhower uses commonplace, pathos, and kairos to construct an energizing speech for his troops to march to victory&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1st point
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The speech uses commonplaces about freedom and democracy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Contrasts the Germans and the Allies&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not just American commonplaces, more universal&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;[will analyze quotes from speech here]&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Commonplaces remind soldiers what they’re fighting for&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Commonplaces that soldiers relate to effectively prepare them to fight with passion&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2nd point
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Eisenhower uses pathos for motivation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Discusses “tyranny” of Nazis and their atrocities&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Supposed to evoke anger against germans and pity for victims&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Helps elevate drive to push forward and succeed&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Appeal to emotion is needed to ensure soldiers are passionate about their fight&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3rd point
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strongest motivating force in speech is kairos&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Uses recent allied victories to show that Germany is no longer dominating&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the speech was earlier in the war, things would look much more bleak and would be harder to motivate&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the US hadn’t started throwing their support from the mainland, also would’ve been more bleak&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Multiple factors combined together create the right moment for an invasion and right time for speech to motivate&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conclusion
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wartime creates opportune moments for great civic events&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Eisenhower’s speech effectively uses commonplaces that are heightened by the war to motivate troops&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pathos against German atrocities is another effective motivator&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Most importantly, the kairos of the situation gives Eisenhower’s speech credibility and strength&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Three rhetorical elements combine to drive Allied forces to victory on D-Day&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2016/09/12/civic-artifact-speech-outline.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2016/09/12/civic-artifact-speech-outline.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rcl</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Thousand Splendid Suns</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/atss.gif&quot; alt=&quot;A Thousand Splendid Suns Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To kick off my first “real” passion post, I’ve decided I’ll start with discussing one of my favorite books, &lt;em&gt;A Thousand Splendid Suns&lt;/em&gt;, by Khaled Hosseini. I’m not going to reveal any spoilers about any of the books I write about just in case anyone decides they want to read one of them, but I will talk about what the books are about and my reactions to them, among other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Thousand Splendid Suns&lt;/em&gt; was assigned to me as a summer reading book coming into my senior year of high school, and, as I had felt for most of my other summer reading books in my lifetime, I did not have high hopes. I was expecting another boring book that I’d have to slog through in preparation for the first day of class. I love reading, but the type of books given for summer assignments aren’t typically up my alley. &lt;em&gt;A Thousand Splendid Suns&lt;/em&gt; blew me away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book follows two womens’ lives, Mariam and Laila, in war-torn Afghanistan. Both womens’ lives are filled with incredible hardships, and they’re constantly struggling to find happiness. The writing is intense and gritty, and as I was reading I was almost afraid of turning to the next page for fear of what would happen. The book gives an unfortunately accurate view of what women faced (and still face) living in such a stricken area. It also raises moral and ethical questions stemming from some decisions that the main characters make. Overall, the book was a smooth read, with a direct, clear language that emphasized the bluntness of the existence portrayed in the novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would recommend that anyone who enjoys reading even just a little to read this book. It pulls you right in; I was invested in the characters almost immediately. &lt;em&gt;A Thousand Splendid Suns&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/09/06/thousand-suns.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/09/06/thousand-suns.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rhetoric Wins Wars</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In rhetoric, &lt;em&gt;kairos&lt;/em&gt;, the Greek concept of the “opportune moment,” plays an important role in defining what makes a rhetorical or civic moment “great.” One such example of an incredibly great civic and rhetorical moment was Dwight D. Eisenhower’s famous speech to his troops on June 6 , 1944—D-Day.  Eisenhower, the then Supreme Allied Commander in Europe, delivers a brief, 243 word  speech to the men about to storm the beaches. The content of the speech is passionate, first starting by stating the cause the soldiers are fighting for. He says the men are bringing about the, “destruction of the German war machine, the elimination of Nazi tyranny over oppressed peoples of Europe, and security for ourselves in a free world.” His words here and later in the speech are examples of &lt;em&gt;pathos,&lt;/em&gt;  appealing to the emotions of the soldiers to get them riled up for fighting the Germans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/dday_landing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;D-Day Invasion&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;the invasion of Normandy, June 6, 1944&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real meat of the speech, however, comes a little later, and it strikes at the core of the power of kairos. Eisenhower changes tune, saying, “But this is the year 1944,” meaning to emphasize the time that has passed since the crushing victories of the German blitzkriegs between 1939-1941. He goes on to list the victories the Allies have had over the Germans in the recent years. He discusses the Allies’ dismantling of the German’s air and ground forces. He poignantly sums it up by saying, “The tide has turned.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timing of this speech within the context of the invasion that was about to take place, as well as what had occurred in the years leading up to D-Day, all combine to create the perfect storm which allows Eisenhower to beautifully motivate and excite his soldiers. The concept of kairos comes into place here so perfectly. Although the Allies had been having more successful operations, D-Day was an essential invasion which needed to succeed to allow the Allies to continue pushing the Germans back. Eisenhower uses these past victories to push his men to believe that yes, they can win the battle, they can continue their previous successes, and yes, they can finally strike a truly destructive blow into Nazi Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2016/08/30/first-rcl-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/rcl/2016/08/30/first-rcl-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>rcl</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My First Passion Post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my passion blog! Here I will have posts about a particular passion of my choosing. Currently I have narrowed the selection down to two different passions. My first choice is reading—I’ve been a voracious reader for as long as I can remember, and I always love talking about books I’ve read or plan to read. For each blog post, I would choose a book I’ve read and talk about what I liked or didn’t like about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other choice is skiing—similar to reading, I’ve been a skier since early childhood. For a skiing blog, I would talk about techniques for learning, doing tricks, the best mountains and trails to go on, and my past experiences as a skier. Currently I’m leaning toward choosing reading, as I think that option would be more relatable and enjoyable, not to mention a little easier to write about. That’s all for now, check back later for more posts!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/08/23/first-passion-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/passion/2016/08/23/first-passion-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Newbies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/seals.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Circle and Penn State Seal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do Penn State and The Circle community have in common? Two words—their size. One of the many things Mae is awed by as she enters the Circle campus is the vastness of it all, with rolling fields, courts, buildings, art, and so much more. Like many other new Penn Staters, one of the most striking things about Penn State is the sheer size of the campus. One can explore for an entire day and still not have visited every building or hotspot on campus. There’s always something to discover. Mae is dazzled by the interworkings of The Circle and the countless different areas and rooms she is whisked around to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly than the size, however, is the people. Penn State is often described as a “cult,” and, if you come around on gameday, it’s easy to see why it’s described that way. Everyone is so connected to Penn State, and there’s really not much else for miles around other than the university. Although Mae and most other Circlers commute to the campus, it’s very clear that The Circle community is just as self-contained as Penn State. The workers spend much of their time there, either working, attending events, or making use of the copious facilities. Right when Mae starts working there, she attends a big celebration, already being welcomed into the community and folded into the seething mass of people. It is just expected that all the workers will want to make use of everything The Circle offers, much like many people simply expect that every Penn State student will get excited for football games and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important way that Penn State and The Circle differ, however, is through The Circle’s first mantra, introduced by Eamon Bailey: “All that happens must be known.” The moment when SeeChange is introduced and the intentions of The Circle are made more clear is the moment for me, where I felt Penn State and The Circle started to differ the most. The difference started becoming clear when it was introduced what The Circle actually did: consolidate every single thing about someone online into one, TrueYou profile. Then, when the new cameras were introduced and all the uses for them shown, it became very clear that The Circle represented something very, very different than anything we have here at Penn State. Privacy is respected here. There’s nothing even close to the “all that happens must be known” mantra. Sure, we have to carry IDs but that’s mostly to ensure that we actually go here and to allow us to get access to the dining hall and other facilities. To show the difference, we can look at the Schreyer Honors College’s mission statement and contrast it with The Circle’s:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Achieving academic excellence with integrity&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Building a global perspective, and&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Creating opportunities for leadership and civic engagement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, the mission of Schreyer, and of the greater university is far different than the mission (so far) that we have seen from The Circle. For now, a shallow comparison of the two entities reveals several similarities. However, I suspect that as time goes on and the overall goal of The Circle becomes more clear, we will see a sharper divide between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/circle/2016/08/23/first-circle-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/circle/2016/08/23/first-circle-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>circle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Quest to Learn C</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a new programmer, I’m always trying to absorb as much information as possible and learn as many tools as possible. After reading through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://matt.might.net/articles/what-cs-majors-should-know/&quot;&gt;daunting list&lt;/a&gt; of “What every computer science major should know” by Matt Might, I came to the realization that I have a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of work ahead of me. 
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty decent with HTML/CSS (although not programming languages), a result of just playing around in Notepad as early as 7th grade. And the Java class I took in high school, although basic, taught me the fundamentals of “real” programming. Lately, however, I haven’t been doing much of either. I’m not one to just sit around, so I decided to attempt to learn one of the most pervasive languages out there—C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-c&quot;&gt;Why C?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always embraced the philosophy that it’s less about learning specific languages, and more about learning the processes and theory behind everything. Syntax can come later. However, it’s easier to learn theory within the context of one specific language, and C offers a very fundamental approach to programming that helps you understand what’s actually going on inside the computer. Sure, it’s a lot harder than a higher-level language like Python, but that’s what makes it rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;learning&quot;&gt;Learning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to learning C, there’s really no substitute to the classic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/5/5e/The_C_Programming_Language_cover.svg/371px-The_C_Programming_Language_cover.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;the C programming language cover&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Programming-Language-Brian-W-Kernighan/dp/0131103628&quot;&gt;The C Programming Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s tons of other resources out there, from Harvard’s free &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/introduction-computer-science-harvardx-cs50x#!&quot;&gt;CS50x&lt;/a&gt; to countless online tutorials. From what I read, though, the verdict was clear—to best learn C, you have to read K&amp;amp;R. Can you really turn down a textbook written by the &lt;em&gt;creator&lt;/em&gt; of the language? Not to mention its short length of only 270 pages, much more enticing than some 600-page behemoth of dense verbosity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve already started working through it, and although I’m only on Chapter 1, I’m already enjoying myself. I’ll be hosting my code on github so I can work wherever I am. I’ll be making periodic status updates (probably about my increasing levels of frustration and anger) as I get farther. Until then, I’m off to write some more code.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/technology/2016/07/14/learning-c.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/technology/2016/07/14/learning-c.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Installing GalliumOS on a Toshiba Chromebook 2 (2015)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since Apple declined to release new Retina Macbook Pros at WWDC 2016, I’ve been on the hunt for a laptop to tide me over until the eventual release sometime in the fall. While I don’t exactly &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a new laptop just yet (after all, the lab computers at Penn State would be perfectly serviceable for the first few months of my first semester) I decided I would prefer to have something portable to take to class. I wasn’t planning on breaking the bank, so I settled on a Chromebook, and after researching a bit (with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddit.com/r/chromeos&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;) I settled on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Toshiba-Chromebook-CB35-C3300-Backlit-Keyboard/dp/B015806LMM&quot;&gt;Toshiba Chromebook 2&lt;/a&gt;, the 2015 edition with the backlit keyboard and 1920x1080 IPS screen. I was able to find a great deal on a refurbished one for $230.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons Chromebooks are so cheap is that they aren’t often built with high-powered components. My version came with a 1.7 GHz Celeron processor, 4 GB of ram, and a 16 GB SSD. Most limiting, however, it came installed with ChromeOS. ChromeOS, while great for casual web browsing, doesn’t offer much when it comes to setting up a dev environment. While there are options for setting up a full linux environment within ChromeOS (see: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dnschneid/crouton&quot;&gt;Crouton&lt;/a&gt;), I decided I didn’t want ChromeOS a single bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I had to give ChromeOS credit where credit was due. Because it’s so lightweight and its kernel is so optimized, it runs great on the limited hardware most Chromebooks provide. While installing full Linux (and even Windows!) is possible, it’s not always the best, performance-wise, and battery life can take a hit. Adding to the complexity, often it’s a pain to set up drivers and keyboard shortcuts to get your hardware working properly on the new OS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where  &lt;a href=&quot;https://galliumos.org/&quot;&gt;GalliumOS&lt;/a&gt; comes in. I found GalliumOS after searching around a bit, and reading the description convinced me it was what I needed. It’s super lightweight, and optimized almost as much as ChromeOS is, utilizing drivers and core files from the ChromeOS kernel itself to run near seamlessly on many popular Chromebooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/gallium.png&quot; alt=&quot;GalliumOS Homepage&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;the GalliumOS homepage&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a few options when it comes to actually installing GalliumOS. The least invasive involves using a utility called &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrx.org/&quot;&gt;chrx&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a simple step-by-step process which involves enabling Developer Mode (more on that later), running a script to flash the firmware, and then running another script to install GalliumOS alongside ChromeOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said before however, I didn’t want to see ChromeOS &lt;em&gt;at all.&lt;/em&gt; Not to mention there’s other problems with going the dual-boot route. You’ll see a scary white screen warning you of the terrible damage you’ve done to your system (not really) and you’ll always have to enter either &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ctrl+L&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ctrl+D&lt;/code&gt; to enter GalliumOS or ChromeOS, repsectively. And there’s a few minor graphical glitches while booting up. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/osv.png&quot; alt=&quot;os verification example&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;example of the scary white screen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these may be only minor annoyances, bearable to those who don’t want to mess with their system &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; much, I knew I wanted to go the more permanent route, which involves completely flashing the BIOS and installing the GalliumOS .iso from a flash drive. Below are the steps I took.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;preparations&quot;&gt;Preparations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I could get around to actually installing GalliumOS, I needed to get my Chromebook ready. The first thing I did was install a new 128 GB SSD, following &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codedonut.com/chromebook/upgrade-ssd-toshiba-chromebook-2/&quot;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a little scary opening up the Chromebook, but using a plastic spudger tool and starting at the hinges of the laptop made it much easier than expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once inside, I replaced the SSD and removed the hardware write protect screw. Removing this screw and the metallic circle underneath is necessary to allow proper flashing of the BIOS. &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/105587851792537311339/posts/XhTMN2zdkHG&quot;&gt;There are pictures of the inside here&lt;/a&gt;. The screw to remove is right next to the SSD and wifi card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After restoring ChromeOS, I powered off the device and pressed &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Esc+Refresh+Power&lt;/code&gt; and then &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ctrl+D&lt;/code&gt; to put the device into Developer Mode, which allows changes to be made to the core files. After 15 minutes or so, my laptop rebooted and I pressed &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ctrl+D&lt;/code&gt; to get into ChromeOS for the last time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;flashing-the-bios&quot;&gt;Flashing the BIOS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This step couldn’t have been simpler. I used coolstar’s Full ROM which included fixes for the graphical issues and removed the scary white screen. &lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; this also removes the ability to boot ChromeOS, meaning it is possible to brick your device. You can still recover it, but it’s a bit of a process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, while I was in ChromeOS, I opened up a Chrome tab, pressed &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ctrl+Alt+T&lt;/code&gt;, typed “shell,” and then &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; and then pasted the following command into the prompt and pressed enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot; data-lang=&quot;shell&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ~; curl -L -O https://mrchromebox.tech/firmware-util.sh; sudo bash firmware-util.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, if you’ve suddenly decided you want to install Windows instead, you can continue with &lt;a href=&quot;https://coolstar.org/chromebook/windows-install.html&quot;&gt;coolstar’s guide&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, it’s time to make a bootable USB drive of GalliumOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;installing-galliumos&quot;&gt;Installing GalliumOS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/win32diskimager/&quot;&gt;Win32DiskImager&lt;/a&gt;) to make my flash drive after downloading the GalliumOS .iso from their website. All I needed to do to install was plug it in and reboot my device. After following a few onscreen prompts, GalliumOS was installed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;customizing-galliumos&quot;&gt;Customizing GalliumOS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GalliumOS is based on Xubuntu, and while it looks and acts pretty great out of the box, there’s a couple things I did to make it prettier and more functional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking the GalliumOS icon in the bottom left corner brings up a sort of Start Menu. From there, I navigated to Settings, and then Keyboard, and binded &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ctrl+Alt+T&lt;/code&gt; to the command &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;xfce4-terminal&lt;/code&gt;, which opens the Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webupd8.org/2015/01/albert-fast-lightweight-quick-launcher.html&quot;&gt;Albert&lt;/a&gt; which is a task launcher kind of like Synapse or Alfred. I binded it to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Alt+A&lt;/code&gt; and messed around with the functionality. Since the Toshiba Chromebook doesn’t have a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Super&lt;/code&gt; key, I wanted something to quickly launch applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also installed &lt;a href=&quot;http://linrunner.de/en/tlp/tlp.html&quot;&gt;TLP&lt;/a&gt;, which is supposed to improve battery life. I haven’t really been able to test how well my battery is in GalliumOS, but I have not noticed it draining any quicker than I would have expected. TLP is in the Ubuntu repo for 16.04 so all it needs is a simple &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo apt-get intall tlp&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved the bottom panel to the top, shrunk it a bit, and removed the functionality that showed open windows. Then I installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchpad.net/plank&quot;&gt;Plank&lt;/a&gt; to get more of an OSX feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After installing Chrome, I made shortcuts to my Chrome Apps and added them to Plank. Now, even when I’m offline I can edit documents using Google Docs and access my files in Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a member of &lt;a href=&quot;http://desktoppr.co&quot;&gt;Desktoppr.co&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, and I’ve amassed a pretty large selection of beautiful wallpapers. It’s really simple to get a slideshow of wallpapers in the XFCE environemnt. I just right clicked (clicked the touchpad with two fingers) on the desktop, selected to customize it, chose the folder where I downloaded my wallpapers, and checked the box to shuffle wallpapers with a timer. The end result of all this is pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/desktop.png&quot; alt=&quot;Desktop screenshot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;my customized linux setup&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it! I’m completely happy with my laptop, and I’m even second-guessing whether or not I’ll really need the new Macbook Pro when it comes out. This little thing looks beautiful and I haven’t run into any hiccups or slowdowns yet. Certainly a great deal for only $280.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://sosnader.tk/technology/2016/07/11/installing-galliumos-on-chromebook.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://sosnader.tk/technology/2016/07/11/installing-galliumos-on-chromebook.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
